<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?> <rss version="2.0" xml:base="http://www.nasa.gov/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"> <channel> <title>NASA Image of the Day</title>
 <description>The latest NASA &quot;Image of the Day&quot; image.</description>
 <link>http://www.nasa.gov/</link>
 <atom:link rel="self" href="http://www.nasa.gov/rss/dyn/image_of_the_day.rss" />
 <language>en-us</language>
 <managingEditor>yvette.smith-1@nasa.gov</managingEditor>
 <webMaster>brian.dunbar@nasa.gov</webMaster>
 <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
 <item> <title>Orbital Sciences&#039; Antares Rocket and Cygnus Spacecraft at the Launch Pad</title>
 <link>http://www.nasa.gov/content/antares-at-the-pad</link>
 <description>Orbital Sciences Corp. of Dulles, Va., rolled out its Antares rocket and Cygnus spacecraft to the Mid-Atlantic Regional Spaceport Pad-0A at NASA&#039;s Wallops Flight Facility in Wallops Island, Va on Friday, Sept. 13, 2013. The Antares is scheduled to launch Cygnus at 11:16 a.m. EDT on Tuesday, Sept. 17 on a demonstration cargo resupply mission to the International Space Station. Cygnus will deliver about 1,300 pounds (589 kilograms) of cargo, including food and clothing, to the Expedition 37 crew aboard the space station, who will capture and install the spacecraft on Sept. 22 using the station&#039;s robotic arm. Orbital is building and testing its Antares rocket and Cygnus spacecraft under NASA’s Commercial Orbital Transportation Services (COTS) program. Following a successful demonstration mission, Orbital is poised to begin eight cargo flights contracted by NASA to resupply the station. Future flights of Cygnus will significantly increase NASA&#039;s ability to deliver new science investigations to the nation&#039;s only laboratory in microgravity.
Image Credit: NASA/Brea Reeves</description>
 <enclosure url="http://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/styles/946xvariable_height/public/bar_824213.jpg?itok=YjeEIqVj" length="928723" type="image/jpeg" />
 <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nasa.gov/content/antares-at-the-pad</guid>
 <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2013 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
 <source url="http://www.nasa.gov/rss/dyn/image_of_the_day.rss">NASA Image of the Day</source>
</item>
 <item> <title>Arc Across the Planet Saturn</title>
 <link>http://www.nasa.gov/content/arc-across-the-planet-saturn</link>
 <description>Saturn&#039;s rings appear to form a majestic arc over the planet in this image from NASA&#039;s Cassini spacecraft.
This view looks toward the sunlit side of the rings from about 17 degrees above the ringplane. The image was taken with the Cassini spacecraft wide-angle camera on June 15, 2013 using a spectral filter sensitive to wavelengths of near-infrared light centered at 705 nanometers.
The view was acquired at a distance of approximately 657,000 miles (1.1 million kilometers) from Saturn and at a Sun-Saturn-spacecraft, or phase, angle of 2 degrees. Image scale is 37 miles (60 kilometers) per pixel.
The Cassini-Huygens mission is a cooperative project of NASA, the European Space Agency and the Italian Space Agency. The Jet Propulsion Laboratory, a division of the California Institute of Technology in Pasadena, manages the mission for NASA&#039;s Science Mission Directorate, Washington, D.C. The Cassini orbiter and its two onboard cameras were designed, developed and assembled at JPL. The imaging operations center is based at the Space Science Institute in Boulder, Colo.
For more information about the Cassini-Huygens mission visit http://www.nasa.gov/cassini and http://saturn.jpl.nasa.gov.
Image Credit: NASA/JPL-Caltech/Space Science Institute</description>
 <enclosure url="http://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/styles/946xvariable_height/public/pia17131.jpg?itok=1XVrrYU2" length="443039" type="image/jpeg" />
 <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nasa.gov/content/arc-across-the-planet-saturn</guid>
 <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2013 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
 <source url="http://www.nasa.gov/rss/dyn/image_of_the_day.rss">NASA Image of the Day</source>
</item>
 <item> <title>Expedition 36 Soyuz Landing</title>
 <link>http://www.nasa.gov/content/expedition-36-soyuz-landing</link>
 <description>The Soyuz TMA-08M spacecraft with Expedition 36 Commander Pavel Vinogradov of the Russian Federal Space Agency (Roscosmos), Flight Engineer Alexander Misurkin of Roscosmos and Flight Engineer Chris Cassidy of NASA aboard, is seen as it lands in a remote area near the town of Zhezkazgan, Kazakhstan, on Wednesday, Sept. 11, 2013 (Sept. 10 EDT). Vinogradov, Misurkin and Cassidy returned to Earth after five and a half months on the International Space Station.
Image Credit: NASA/Bill Ingalls</description>
 <enclosure url="http://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/styles/946xvariable_height/public/201309110001hq.jpg?itok=lxNHV2Q7" length="3714416" type="image/jpeg" />
 <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nasa.gov/content/expedition-36-soyuz-landing</guid>
 <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2013 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
 <source url="http://www.nasa.gov/rss/dyn/image_of_the_day.rss">NASA Image of the Day</source>
</item>
 <item> <title>Expedition 36 Crew to Return to Earth</title>
 <link>http://www.nasa.gov/content/expedition-36-crew-to-return-to-earth</link>
 <description>In preparation for the Expedition 36 return to Earth, Commander Pavel Vinogradov of Russia&#039;s Federal Space Agency (Roscosmos) handed over control of the International Space Station Monday, Sept. 9, 2013 at 2:25 p.m. EDT in a traditional Change of Command Ceremony. Roscosmos Flight Engineer Fyodor Yurchikhin will take over command and officially lead Expedition 37 when Expedition 36 undocks Tuesday at 7:35 p.m.
Going home with Vinogradov are Flight Engineers Chris Cassidy of NASA and Alexander Misurkin of Roscosmos, who arrived at the station March 28. They will land a few hours later in their Soyuz TMA-08M spacecraft at 10:58 p.m. (8:58 a.m. Wednesday Kazakhstan time). Soyuz landing coverage begins Tuesday on NASA TV at 4 p.m. with farewell and hatch closure.
In the bottom half of this photo, left to right, are Vinogradov and Flight Engineers Karen Nyberg of NASA and Misurkin. In the top half of the photo are, left to right, Flight Engineers Luca Parmitano of the European Space Agency, Cassidy, and Yurchikhin. This photo was taken on June 8, 2013.
Image Credit: NASA</description>
 <enclosure url="http://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/styles/946xvariable_height/public/iss036e006695.jpg?itok=VkCGmS1G" length="1611273" type="image/jpeg" />
 <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nasa.gov/content/expedition-36-crew-to-return-to-earth</guid>
 <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2013 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
 <source url="http://www.nasa.gov/rss/dyn/image_of_the_day.rss">NASA Image of the Day</source>
</item>
 <item> <title>Hubble Catches a Spiral in the Air Pump</title>
 <link>http://www.nasa.gov/content/goddard/hubble-catches-a-spiral-in-the-air-pump</link>
 <description>Lying more than 110 million light-years away from Earth in the constellation of Antlia (The Air Pump) is the spiral galaxy IC 2560, shown here in an image from NASA/ESA Hubble Space Telescope. At this distance it is a relatively nearby spiral galaxy, and is part of the Antlia cluster — a group of over 200 galaxies held together by gravity. This cluster is unusual; unlike most other galaxy clusters, it appears to have no dominant galaxy within it.
In this image, it is easy to spot IC 2560&#039;s spiral arms and barred structure. This spiral is what astronomers call a Seyfert-2 galaxy, a kind of spiral galaxy characterized by an extremely bright nucleus and very strong emission lines from certain elements — hydrogen, helium, nitrogen, and oxygen. The bright center of the galaxy is thought to be caused by the ejection of huge amounts of super-hot gas from the region around a central black hole.
There is a story behind the naming of this quirky constellation — Antlia was originally named antlia pneumatica by French astronomer Abbé Nicolas Louis de Lacaille, in honor of the invention of the air pump in the 17th century.
Credit: Hubble/European Space Agency and NASA</description>
 <enclosure url="http://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/styles/946xvariable_height/public/potw1335a_0.jpg?itok=hSBn42wR" length="161613" type="image/jpeg" />
 <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nasa.gov/content/goddard/hubble-catches-a-spiral-in-the-air-pump</guid>
 <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2013 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
 <source url="http://www.nasa.gov/rss/dyn/image_of_the_day.rss">NASA Image of the Day</source>
</item>
 <item> <title>LADEE Launches From NASA Wallops</title>
 <link>http://www.nasa.gov/content/ladee-launches-from-nasa-wallops</link>
 <description>A Minotaur V rocket carrying NASA&#039;s Lunar Atmosphere and Dust Environment Explorer (LADEE) lifts off from at NASA&#039;s Wallops Flight Facility in Virginia on Friday, Sept. 6, 2013.  LADEE is a robotic mission designed to orbit the moon where and provide unprecedented information about the environment around the moon and give scientists a better understanding of other planetary bodies in our solar system and beyond.
 
Credit: NASA/Chris Perry</description>
 <enclosure url="http://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/styles/946xvariable_height/public/img_4837.jpg?itok=K0iwbZL0" length="383642" type="image/jpeg" />
 <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nasa.gov/content/ladee-launches-from-nasa-wallops</guid>
 <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2013 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
 <source url="http://www.nasa.gov/rss/dyn/image_of_the_day.rss">NASA Image of the Day</source>
</item>
 <item> <title>LADEE Ready for Launch</title>
 <link>http://www.nasa.gov/content/ladee-ready-for-launch-0</link>
 <description>In an attempt to answer prevailing questions about our moon, NASA is making final preparations to launch a probe at 11:27 p.m. EDT Friday, Sept. 6, from NASA&#039;s Wallops Flight Facility on Wallops Island, Va.
	
	The small car-sized Lunar Atmosphere and Dust Environment Explorer (LADEE) is a robotic mission that will orbit the moon to gather detailed information about the structure and composition of the thin lunar atmosphere and determine whether dust is being lofted into the lunar sky. A thorough understanding of these characteristics of our nearest celestial neighbor will help researchers understand other bodies in the solar system, such as large asteroids, Mercury, and the moons of outer planets.
	
	For more information about the LADEE mission, visit: http://www.nasa.gov/ladee.
Image Credit: NASA</description>
 <enclosure url="http://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/styles/946xvariable_height/public/ladee_9.4.13_nasa_edge_0.jpg?itok=N3UPLl2_" length="18678648" type="image/jpeg" />
 <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nasa.gov/content/ladee-ready-for-launch-0</guid>
 <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2013 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
 <source url="http://www.nasa.gov/rss/dyn/image_of_the_day.rss">NASA Image of the Day</source>
</item>
 <item> <title>LADEE Spin Test</title>
 <link>http://www.nasa.gov/content/ladee-spin-test</link>
 <description>During preparations for NASA&#039;s Lunar Atmosphere and Dust Environment Explorer (LADEE) observatory launch on Sept. 6, 2013, the spacecraft went through final preparations and close-outs, which included checking alignment after its cross-country shipment, checking the propulsion system for leaks, inspecting and repairing solar panels, and final electrical tests. After these activities were completed, more challenging portions of the launch preparations began: spin testing and fueling.
To make sure that the spacecraft is perfectly balanced for flight, engineers mounted it onto a spin table and rotate it at high speeds, approximately one revolution per second. The team measured any offsets during the spinning, and then added small weights to the spacecraft to balance it. Once the spacecraft was balanced dry, the team loaded the propulsion tanks with fuel, oxidizer, and pressurant. The spin testing was performed again &quot;wet,&quot; or with fuel, in order to see if the balance changed with the full fuel tanks.
Engineers from NASA&#039;s Ames Research Center in Moffett Field, Calif., have now successfully completed launch preparation activities for LADEE, which has been encapsulated into the nose-cone of the Minotaur V rocket at NASA&#039;s Wallops Flight Facility in Virginia. LADEE is ready to launch when the window opens on Friday.
Image Credit: NASA</description>
 <enclosure url="http://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/styles/946xvariable_height/public/ladee_spin_2_in_motion_0_0.jpg?itok=yNhf69rE" length="8124858" type="image/jpeg" />
 <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nasa.gov/content/ladee-spin-test</guid>
 <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2013 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
 <source url="http://www.nasa.gov/rss/dyn/image_of_the_day.rss">NASA Image of the Day</source>
</item>
 <item> <title>NASA Air Pollution Study to Fly Over Houston</title>
 <link>http://www.nasa.gov/content/nasa-air-pollution-study-to-fly-over-houston</link>
 <description>Two NASA aircraft equipped with scientific instruments will fly over the Houston area throughout September of 2013 as part of a multi-year airborne science mission to help scientists better understand how to measure and forecast air quality from space.
The aircraft are part of NASA&#039;s five-year DISCOVER-AQ study, which stands for Deriving Information on Surface conditions from Column and Vertically Resolved Observations Relevant to Air Quality.
This two-engine B200 King Air aircraft, shown on the tarmac at NASA Langley Research Center in Hampton, Va., will collect data for the DISCOVER-AQ study looking downward from an altitude of 26,000 feet. The plane&#039;s instruments will look down at the Earth&#039;s surface, much like a satellite, and measure particulate and gaseous air pollution.
&gt; Read More
Image Credit: NASA</description>
 <enclosure url="http://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/styles/946xvariable_height/public/kingair_0_0.jpg?itok=HhgjtBD8" length="230346" type="image/jpeg" />
 <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nasa.gov/content/nasa-air-pollution-study-to-fly-over-houston</guid>
 <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2013 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
 <source url="http://www.nasa.gov/rss/dyn/image_of_the_day.rss">NASA Image of the Day</source>
</item>
 <item> <title>Astronaut Candidate Survival Training</title>
 <link>http://www.nasa.gov/content/astronaut-candidate-survival-training</link>
 <description>The countenance of astronaut candidate Christina M. Hammock signals her success at fire-starting, a technique that will help sustain her for three days in the wilderness. As the first phase of their extensive training program along the way to become full-fledged astronauts, eight new candidates spent three days in the wild participating in their wilderness survival training, near Rangeley, Maine.
Image Credit: NASA</description>
 <enclosure url="http://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/styles/946xvariable_height/public/jsc2013e078108.jpg?itok=mRLN5s9b" length="1025387" type="image/jpeg" />
 <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nasa.gov/content/astronaut-candidate-survival-training</guid>
 <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
 <source url="http://www.nasa.gov/rss/dyn/image_of_the_day.rss">NASA Image of the Day</source>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
